<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
	<channel>
		<title>Animancer</title>
		<link>https://kybernetikgames.github.io/animancer</link>
		<description />
		<copyright>2018</copyright>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 09:25:21 GMT</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 09:25:21 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<item>
			<title>Animancer v2.0 - Mix Multiple AnimatorControllers</title>
			<link>https://kybernetikgames.github.io/animancer/blog/2018/10/animancer-v2-0</link>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;I just released update to my animation system with a big new feature: you can now use regular AnimatorController&lt;strong&gt;s&lt;/strong&gt; in Animancer. Emphasis on the '&lt;strong&gt;s&lt;/strong&gt;' because you can play and blend between multiple AnimatorControllers at once as if each was its own sub-state-machine. So you could make a controller containing nothing but a single Blend Tree for movement and still mix it with all your other animations separately.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
			<author>Kailas</author>
			<guid>https://kybernetikgames.github.io/animancer/blog/2018/10/animancer-v2-0</guid>
			<pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
			<content:encoded>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://u3d.as/19Xd"&gt;Animancer Lite: Free&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://u3d.as/19Xb"&gt;Animancer Pro: $20&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="../docs/introduction#feature-comparison"&gt;Differences between versions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://animancer.github.io/"&gt;New online user manual&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just released update to my animation system with a big new feature: you can now use regular AnimatorController&lt;strong&gt;s&lt;/strong&gt; in Animancer. Emphasis on the '&lt;strong&gt;s&lt;/strong&gt;' because you can play and blend between multiple AnimatorControllers at once as if each was its own sub-state-machine. So you could make a controller containing nothing but a single Blend Tree for movement and still mix it with all your other animations separately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the great feedback I got when releasing v1.3 I've also rewritten the entire User Manual and converted it from the old PDF &lt;a href="https://animancer.github.io"&gt;into an awesome website&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everything is hopefully explained a lot more clearly now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The package includes some demo scenes to show how everything is set up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The full &lt;a href="../api/Animancer/AnimancerController/"&gt;API documentation&lt;/a&gt; has been compiled into it from all the XML comments in my code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I've also done some &lt;a href="../docs/source-code-overview/performance-benchmarks"&gt;Performance Benchmarks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And added a section describing various &lt;a href="../docs/unity-bugs/"&gt;Unity Bugs&lt;/a&gt; I've run into while developing the system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As usual, I'm looking for as much feedback as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Animancer v1.3 Released - Why aren't you using it</title>
			<link>https://kybernetikgames.github.io/animancer/blog/2018/09/animancer-v1-3</link>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://assetstore.unity.com/packages/tools/animation/animancer-lite-116516"&gt;Animancer Lite is Free&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://assetstore.unity.com/packages/tools/animation/animancer-pro-116514"&gt;Animancer Pro costs $10&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
			<author>Kailas</author>
			<guid>https://kybernetikgames.github.io/animancer/blog/2018/09/animancer-v1-3</guid>
			<pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
			<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://assetstore.unity.com/packages/tools/animation/animancer-lite-116516"&gt;Animancer Lite is Free&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://assetstore.unity.com/packages/tools/animation/animancer-pro-116514"&gt;Animancer Pro costs $10&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've just released a fairly minor update to my Animancer plugin and I put a lot of work into improving the store page and user manual so I'd like to get your feedback in two main areas:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you see the store page and decide not to even try out the free version, can you tell me why? Obviously there's not much I can do about it if you're not currently using animations at all, but if you have other reasons I'd love to hear them. Is it unclear what the plugin actually does or what its advantages are? Do you disagree with any of the assertions I've made about the problems with Mecanim? Do you just not care enough about those problems to try something new? Are my store images too programmer-arty?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you do try it out and decide you don't like it, can you tell me why? Does it not do what you expected? Do you need features only available in the Pro version but are unwilling to spend $10 for something like this? Am I asking too many questions?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've also changed the feature restrictions of the Lite version. All the same features are still pro-only (cross fading, layers, mixers), but now the Lite version lets you use them in the Unity Editor so you can try them out before spending the money on Pro. Hopefully that will avoid people being reluctant to take a leap of faith on what the Pro version can actually do. The actual change log is on the store page if you're interested.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Animancer v1.2 Released</title>
			<link>https://kybernetikgames.github.io/animancer/blog/2018/08/animancer-v1-2</link>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;I've just released an update for Animancer - a code-based replacement for Unity's Mecanim Animator Controllers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
			<author>Kailas</author>
			<guid>https://kybernetikgames.github.io/animancer/blog/2018/08/animancer-v1-2</guid>
			<pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
			<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I've just released an update for Animancer - a code-based replacement for Unity's Mecanim Animator Controllers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asset Store Links: &lt;a href="https://assetstore.unity.com/packages/tools/animation/animancer-lite-116516"&gt;Lite Version (Free)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://assetstore.unity.com/packages/tools/animation/animancer-pro-116514"&gt;Pro Version ($10)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Functionality-wise it's a very small update since I focussed on improving things people have been having trouble with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The store page and user manual should now do a much better job of explaining what the plugin actually does.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added some inspector warnings and a section to the manual explaining how Wrap Modes are used. Since Animancer supports wrap modes and Mecanim doesn't (and therefore the model importer doesn't even show them unless set to Legacy mode) some users were getting unexpected results from &lt;code&gt;WrapMode.Once&lt;/code&gt; without even realising that the wrap mode was set.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[Pro-Only] Added the ability to control the Weight of each layer and to fade them like states.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please let me know if you have any feedback or questions, especially if you feel the store page still doesn't do a good job of explaining what the plugin does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up I plan to finish off a massive update to Weaver which adds a static asset referencing system inspired by the &lt;a href="http://docs.godotengine.org/en/3.0/getting_started/step_by_step/singletons_autoload.html"&gt;Auto Load&lt;/a&gt; feature from the Godot engine. Among other things, it allows you to write amazingly robust and efficient pseudo-singletons that look like this: &lt;code&gt;[AssetInstance] public static readonly GameManager Instance;&lt;/code&gt; (not that I'd ever advocate actually having a script called GameManager).&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Animancer v1.1 - The answer to all your animation problems (well, some of them at least)</title>
			<link>https://kybernetikgames.github.io/animancer/blog/2018/05/animancer-v1-1</link>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;Asset Store Links: &lt;a href="https://assetstore.unity.com/packages/tools/animation/animancer-lite-116516"&gt;Lite Version Free&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://assetstore.unity.com/packages/tools/animation/animancer-pro-116514"&gt;Pro Version $10&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
			<author>Kailas</author>
			<guid>https://kybernetikgames.github.io/animancer/blog/2018/05/animancer-v1-1</guid>
			<pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
			<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Asset Store Links: &lt;a href="https://assetstore.unity.com/packages/tools/animation/animancer-lite-116516"&gt;Lite Version Free&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://assetstore.unity.com/packages/tools/animation/animancer-pro-116514"&gt;Pro Version $10&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the major changes affect the Pro version, but I've also refined the API and documentation a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[Pro-Only] Added support for animation layers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[Pro-Only] Added methods for automatically calculating thresholds for AnimationMixers (equivalent to Blend Trees).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also found a rather surprising bug in the way Mecanim handles Blend Trees which Animancer doesn't have. If you make a tree that blends between two speeds such as an idle and a run, the blended weights of each of them are not actually linearly proportional to the parameter value you set. If you set the parameter to halfway between the two, the root motion velocity you get out of it won't be halfway between the two animations. I've reported the bug to Unity and they confirmed it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please check it out and let me know if you have any questions/problems/feature requests.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Animancer v1.0 - Make Animation Great Again</title>
			<link>https://kybernetikgames.github.io/animancer/blog/2018/05/animancer-v1-0</link>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;Check out Animancer, a plugin which lets you play animations without an Animator Controller&lt;/p&gt;</description>
			<author>Kailas</author>
			<guid>https://kybernetikgames.github.io/animancer/blog/2018/05/animancer-v1-0</guid>
			<pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
			<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Check out Animancer, a plugin which lets you play animations without an Animator Controller&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like many others, I've been greatly frustrated with the way Mecanim works; in particular the need to set up redundant state machines and the way it forces you to litter your code with magic strings and management code to ensure it's actually doing what you want. So I decided to make my own alternative using the new Playables system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My system has two versions available on the Asset Store:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://assetstore.unity.com/packages/tools/animation/animancer-lite-116516"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Animancer Lite&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: free, no Cross Fading, no Animation Mixers (Blend Trees), and no source code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://assetstore.unity.com/packages/tools/animation/animancer-pro-116514"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Animancer Pro&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: $10, all features enabled, and all scripts are included as .cs files rather than pre-compiled as a DLL.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I submitted it using 2017.3 so you'll need that version (or later) to download it. If you'd like to use it on an earlier version, let me know and I'll see what needs to be done to get it working on your version (it requires at least 2017.1 for the Playables system and I know there have been some API changes since then).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's how it works:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instead of creating an AnimatorController asset you add an AnimancerController component to your object.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Inspector looks very similar to the Legacy Animation component: it has an array of Animations and a Play Automatically toggle (which plays the first animation in the array).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The key difference between Animancer and Legacy is that you don't actually need to add clips to the Animations array; instead, you pass them directly into the Play method.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For example: you could make an Attack script with a public AnimationClip attackAnimation; and then just call animancer.Play(attackAnimation);. This Dependency Injection means that your script isn't dependant on the correct AnimatorController being assigned and having a particular state identified by a magic string. The Attack script needs an animation, therefore it is responsible for providing one, or it might have an array of them to perform a combo, or it could get them from your currently equipped weapon. The system can be used however you like.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also unlike the Legacy system, Animancer still supports the other cool features of Mecanim like animation retargeting, root motion, and blend trees.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I've included a couple of example scripts in the screenshots on the store page along with some example Use Cases which compare the way you could approach various tasks using Mecanim vs. Animancer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately upgrading from Lite to Pro will cause Unity to lose any references to Animancer scripts because Lite has a precompiled DLL and Pro has the scripts loose in the project. I've written a simple utility script to track down missing scripts in all prefabs and scenes, and help you fix their references. Just &lt;a href="https://pastebin.com/DMy5w1y6"&gt;grab the script from here&lt;/a&gt; and save it anywhere in your project (Assets/Plugins/Animancer/Editor is a good place for it). Then you can select an object with a missing script and click the &amp;quot;Find and Fix Missing Scripts&amp;quot; button in the inspector to get started. I've tested it and it works pretty well, but I only wrote it yesterday and it needs some serious polish before I properly include it in the next version of Animancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with any new asset I'm keen to hear people's opinions, feedback, and feature suggestions so I can improve the system.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>